<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guice on Jakob Külzer</title>
    <link>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/tags/guice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guice on Jakob Külzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <managingEditor>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Jakob Külzer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 13:59:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/tags/guice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OSGI, Guice, and Peaberry: first steps</title>
      <link>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2013/02/27/osgi-guice-and-peaberry-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 13:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</author>
      <guid>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2013/02/27/osgi-guice-and-peaberry-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to get Google Guice and Peaberry to work in my OSGI projects for a while. Google Guice is a great dependency injection framework, and Peaberry promises to bridge the gap between OSGI services and dependency injection.
However, getting Peaberry to work was not trivial, mostly because there aren&amp;rsquo;t many docs and the quality of the docs is somewhat lacking. The best piece is still this pdf Peaberry - blending services and extensions, but it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of information in very little space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Guice and Scope Mixing</title>
      <link>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2012/12/11/google-guice-and-scope-mixing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 13:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</author>
      <guid>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2012/12/11/google-guice-and-scope-mixing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a small Java application I wrote a few years ago for some bug fixes and in the process of making it better, I introduced Google Guice, my favourite dependency injection framework. On of the great features of Guice is that it supports different scopes for injection. Per default, Guice will return a new object for every request. But sometimes you want to objects to be created a bit less liberally, for example, you want a certain object to be created only once.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
