<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Development on Jakob Külzer&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/tags/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Development on Jakob Külzer&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <managingEditor>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 11:27:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/tags/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration and Action</title>
      <link>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2018/03/30/inspiration-and-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 11:27:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</author>
      <guid>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2018/03/30/inspiration-and-action/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently re-reading Growing Object-Oriented Software, Guided by Tests, and this quote really spoke to me:
 We should be taught not to wait for inspiration to start a thing. Action always generates inspiration. Inspiration seldom generates action.
&amp;ndash; Frank Tibolt
 I think of myself as a perfectionist, the kind of person that hates to produce anything short of flawless. And while this is great quality to have because it drives me to improve and progress, it&amp;rsquo;s also incredibly crippling and frustrating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Golang and Graphviz to Visualize Complex Grails Applications</title>
      <link>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2014/05/03/using-golang-and-graphviz-to-visualize-complex-grails-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 13:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</author>
      <guid>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2014/05/03/using-golang-and-graphviz-to-visualize-complex-grails-applications/</guid>
      <description>At work we are maintaining several large and complex grails applications. In order to improve stability and reliability, we&amp;rsquo;re trying to increase test coverage. But as with all projects, time and resources are limited. In order to get a better understanding of what parts of the application are more important than others, I decided to use Graphviz to help me get a better overview of our applications.
Meet Graphviz I discovered my love for the dot language when I used it years ago to analyze template hierarchies in a proprietary CMS system I worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case for Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2013/06/01/the-case-for-continuous-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 13:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</author>
      <guid>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2013/06/01/the-case-for-continuous-integration/</guid>
      <description>In my career as a software developer, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to appreciate the principles of Continuous Integration (CI). It forces you to do the hard things early and often and thus helps you reduce risk during development. It forces you to write tests, and be responsible about what you check in. All in all, good qualities and something that every development team should aspire to. Or so I thought. Reality is different, and so far almost every development team I have interacted with is deadly afraid of doing CI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Developer Happiness and Productivity</title>
      <link>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2013/04/03/on-developer-happiness-and-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>jakob.kuelzer@gmail.com (Jakob Külzer)</author>
      <guid>https://ilikeorangutans.github.io/2013/04/03/on-developer-happiness-and-productivity/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the idea for this blog post in my mind for a long time. It is based on all my personal experiences and observations over the past years and is in no way scientific. It is my personal opinion, and even though this is how I perceive the world, it might not be true for other people. With that said, let&amp;rsquo;s jump to the core of things.
 A happy developer is a productive developer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>